A Guide to the Papers of Ann Beattie
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ann Beattie 1972-1996
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10414-z
This collection consists of ca. 3500 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Signed student evaluations are restricted. Other material is open to the public.
Acquisition Information
This collection has been loaned to the University of Virginia Library on March 20 and April 24, 1996 by Ann Beattie, Charlottesville, Virginia.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of Ann Beattie consist of correspondence with editors, publishers, colleagues, fans, and friends; typescripts of books including Another You and Falling in Place; short stories from Burning house, Secrets and surprises, What was mine, and Where you'll find me; essays; a commencement address at American University; and legal papers especially contracts.
Also printed material; broadsides; interviews; book reviews; articles about Beattie; class evaluations from the University of Virginia; photographs; newsclippings; itineraries; posters advertising readings; published books and book catalogs; bookcover artwork and dust jackets; mailing list; a cassette tape of a reading for "Weekend edition"; and manuscripts and printed chapbooks by other authors.
Contents List
- Series I: Manuscripts of Books, Short Stories, & Other Work
  - Another You ca. 1995, TMs (Box 1)
    with autograph corrections (3 folders)
  - Another You ca. 1995, TMs (Box 1)
    Bound Draft
  - Another You ca. 1995, TMs (Box 2)
    Spiral Bound Typescript
  - Articles and Other Writings re Bob Adelman n.d. (Box 2)
  - Commencement Address at the American University 1983 May 8 (Box 2)
  - Falling in Place ca. 1980, TMs (Box 2)
    with autograph corrections (2 folders)
  - Learning to Fall n.d., TMs (Box 2)
    First Draft with autograph corrections
  - Learning to Fall n.d., TMs (Box 2)
  - Learning to Fall n.d., TMs (EC) (Box 3)
  - Life by Lynne Sherbondy 1991, TMs (Box 3)
    based on a short story by Ann Beattie, Third Draft
  - Love Always- Chapter 12, A Sketch n.d., TMs (Box 3)
  - Picturing Will 1989, TMs (Box 3)
    with autograph corrections (4 folders)
  - "The Old Man and the Fish" n.d., TMs (Box 4)
    (2 folders)
  - Short Stories from The Burning Houseca. 1982 (Box 4)
  - Short Stories from Secrets and Surprisesca. 1979 (Box 4)
  - Short Stories from What Was Mineca. 1991 (Box 4)
  - Short Stories from Where You'll Find Meca. 1986 (Box 4)
  - Short Stories - B Tiles 1996, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Short Stories, C-W, and untitled ca. 1972-1994 (Box 5)
  - Short Stories, Essays, etc. - Published Versions (2 folders) 1972-1993 (Box 6)
  - A Vintage Thunderbird Screenplay by Robert Clem 1981 (Box 6)
    based on a story by Ann Beattie (3rd Draft)
  - Weekend ca. 1981 (Box 6)
    with many autograph corrections
  - Weekend 1981 (Box 6)
    Third Revision
  - Weekend 1982 Jan 21 (Box 6)
    Final Script
  - Writings by Other Authors 1982-1990, n.d. (Box 6)
- Series II: Correspondence and Other Papers
  - Book Catalog Notices of Ann Beattie's Books 1987-1992 (Box 7)
  - Book Jackets & Cover Design Material ca. 1990-1995 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence - Doubleday 1975-1977 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence - Editors, Publishers, Magazines, etc. 1975-1989 (Box 7)
    (4 folders)
  - Correspondence - Editors, Publishers, Magazines, etc. 1990-1996 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence - Friends, Colleagues, & Fans 1975-1979 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence -- Friends, Colleagues, & Fans 1980-1995, n.d. (Box 9)
    (6 folders)
  - Correspondence - Friends, Colleagues, & Fans - Postcards ca. 1977-1992 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - Blanche Gregory 1974-1990 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence - Universities, Colleges, etc. 1975-1992 (Box 10)
  - Course Evaluations of Classes taught by Ann Beattie at the University of Virginia 1982 Fall (Box 10)
  - Essays, Articles, and Reviews by Ann Beattie 1981-1996 (Box 10)
  - Interviews 1980-1996 (Box 11)
  - Legal Papers, Contracts, etc. 1976-1992 (Box 11)
  - Photographs 1977-1991 (Box 11)
  - Printed Material & Miscellaneous 1980-1997 (Box 11)
  - Publicity 1988-1991, n.d. (Box 11)
  - Reviews 1974-1995 (Box 12)
  - Royalty Statements 1978-1987 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Books, Foreign & American Editions 1978-1995 (Box 12)
    (7 volumes)
- Cassette Tape Recording
  - Ann Beattie Reading for Weekend Edition 1988 Jan 17 (Box 12)
    (National Public Radio)
- Miscellaneous
  - 2 Interviews of Ann Beattie in Simmons Review and CHALFA's Our Community & The Arts1982 & 1985
  - 3 Posters advertising readings by Ann Beattie n.d.
    at the Rhode Island School of Design, the First and Second Church of Boston, and the Day Writers Series
  - Publicity Poster Board of Ann Beattie n.d.
    in color